Hello, and welcome to Lesson 11 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
您好，欢迎来到Wolfram U的微积分入门课程第11课。
The topic for this lesson is the chain rule, so let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
本课程的主题是链式规则，因此让我们从本课程的简要概述开始。
Recall that if you have two functions f and g, then the composition of f and g will
回想一下，如果你有两个函数f和g，那么f和g的组合就是
take the values of g and then plug them into f. Here’s an example. You have f given by x^2,
求取g的值，然后将其代入f。这是一个例子。你有x ^ 2 给定的f，
and g is just a sine function. If you try and work out f[g[x]], that’s going to be Sin[x]
而g是一个正弦函数。如果您尝试算出f [ g [ x ]]，那将是Sin [ x ]
and then the square of it, so Sin[x], the whole squared, or sine squared x.
然后是它的平方，所以Sin [ x ]是整个平方或正弦平方x。
Now, the rules we have discussed so far—the sum rule, product, et cetera—cannot be used to find
现在，我们到目前为止讨论的规则（求和规则，乘积等）无法用于求出
the derivatives of such compositions, but of course D knows about them.
这些组合函数的导数，但当然Wolfram语言的求导指令D懂得如何求出它们。
What’s required over here is something called the chain rule. The chain rule is what lets you
这里需要的是所谓的链式规则。连锁规则使您可以
find out the derivatives of compositions, and that’s the topic for the lesson:
求出组合函数的导数，这就是本课的主题：
the chain rule and examples for this very powerful rule.
链式规则以及此非常强大的规则的示例。
Let’s begin with a statement of the rule. If you have two functions f and g
让我们从规则的声明开始。如果您有两个函数f和g
and if f is differentiable at g[x] and g is differentiable at x, then the composition is also
并且如果f在g[x]可微而且g在x也可微分，那么组合函数
differentiable at x. The main point now is that the derivative is given by g'[x] on the right
在x处可微分。现在的要点是，导数由右侧的g '[ x ] 给出
and f'[g[x]] on the left. Here’s an example in the abstract setting. D[f[g[x]] is f'[g[x]] times g'[x].
和f '[ g [ x ]]在左侧。这是更加抽象的示例。D [ f [ g [ x ]]是f '[ g [ x ]]乘以g '[ x ]。
So, if I said find the derivative of Sin^2[x], you would first work out the derivative of Sin[x]
因此，如果我们要找出Sin ^ 2 [ x ]的导数，则首先要计算出Sin [ x ] 的导数
and then the derivative of x^2, and then would plug in x with Sin[x]. Okay.
然后计算x ^ 2的导数，然后将x插入Sin[ x ]。
Then you get back the answer 2Cos[x]Sin[x]. Here’s a plot of the function and its derivative,
然后，您得到答案2Cos [ x ] Sin [ x ]。这是函数及其导数的图解，
and notice that the function Sin^2[x] is always non-negative, but its derivative can be
注意到函数Sin ^ 2 [ x ]总是非负的，但其导数可以是
either positive or negative depending upon which portion of the graph you are in.
是正数还是负数，取决于您所处图表的哪一部分。
Okay. As an example of an algebraic function with a composition in it, let’s take
好了。作为其中包含合成的代数函数的示例，让我们来看一下
the square root of x^2 − 1. Now in this case, the inner function is going to be x^2 − 1,
x ^ 2 − 1的平方根。现在，在这种情况下，内部函数将是x ^ 2 − 1，
and the outer one is square root of x, so that’s the composition in this case, g[h[x]].
外部的根是x的平方根，所以在这种情况下就是g [ h [ x ]]的组成。
What you do is you work out the derivative of x^2 − 1, which is 2x, and then work out
您要做的是算出x ^ 2 − 1 的导数，即2 x，然后算出
the derivative of the outer function, and there’s the answer. D gives the same result,
外部函数的导数，就是答案。D给出相同的结果，
and here is a plot of the function and its derivative. Of course because we’re finding
这是函数及其导数的图。当然是因为我们正在寻找
the derivative of the square root of x^2 − 1, there’s nothing on the left of 1 over here.
x ^ 2 − 1的平方根的导数在这里1的左边没有东西。
Okay. Here’s a trig function, Cos[x^2]. Now the inner function over here is x^2;
好的。这是一个三角函数Cos [ x ^ 2]。现在这里的内部函数是x ^ 2;
the outer one is Cos[x]. Let’s first set up the composition, and you get back Cos[x^2] from g[h[x]].
最外面的是Cos [ x ]。让我们首先构造合成函数，然后从g [ h [ x ]] 得到Cos [ x ^ 2 ]。
You work out the derivative of h. That’s 2x. Work out the derivative of g,
您算出h的导数。那是2 x。算出导数g，
and then that’s the answer. And of course, D gives just the same result.
然后就是答案。当然，D给出的结果相同。
Here is a plot of the function and its derivative.
这是函数及其导数的图。
Let’s go on now to talking about the power rule. Now, the power rule is a rule for finding
现在让我们继续讨论幂规则。幂规则探讨的是
the derivative of x^n, but you can make it even more powerful by just composing it
x ^ n的导数，但是您可以通过将它和
with another function g. Okay. If I gave you f[g[x]] with g being some function,
另一个函数g组合来使得它更加好用。好的。如果我给你f [ g [ x ]]并且g是函数，
then the chain rule says that the derivative is ng[x]^(−1 − n)g'[x]. For example, if I said
则链规则表明导数为ng [ x ] ^（-1- n）g '[ x ]。例如，如果我说
find the derivative of (x^4 + 1)^100, you can find it quite easily because all you do is
找到（x ^ 4 + 1）^ 100 的导数，就可以很容易地算出它，实际上这就是
you do 100 times that raised to 99 times the derivative of (x^4 + 1), which is 4x^3.
100乘上（x ^ 4 + 1）的99次方的导数，即4 x ^ 3。
Of course, you don’t have to use a positive here. You could use a fraction like in this example,
当然，指数不一定是正数。您可以使用本示例中的分数，
or you could even use a negative number, and you get back the answer quite easily.
或者甚至可以使用负数，也可以很容易地得到答案。
In this very simple way, you can extend the power rule
通过这种非常简单的方法，您可以扩展幂规则
to find the derivatives of fairly complicated compositions.
求出相当复杂的组合函数的导数。
Okay. Now if you have a product like over here—f[x] is a product of two things over here:
好的。现在，如果您有一个像这里一样的乘积，f [x]是以下这两个因子的乘积：
(3x − 2)^3 and (9x^4 − x +3)^5. You might think that the best way to do it is to expand f.
（3 x -2）^ 3和（9 x ^ 4- − x +3）^ 5。您可能认为最好的方法是展开f。
Well, you could do that and then find the derivative, but that’s going to be a long, messy answer,
好吧，您可以这样做，然后找到导数，但这将是一个漫长而混乱的答案，
so a much better way is to use the product rule and the chain rule together.
因此更好的方法是将乘积规则和链式规则一起使用。
You say first function times the derivative of the second one, and then the second function times
您说第一个函数乘以第二个函数的导数，然后第二个函数乘以
the derivative of the first, and you get back the answer, which is the same as
第一个的导数，然后您得到答案，该答案与
the earlier long answer. In fact, D prefers to use the product rule,
较早的答案相同。实际上，D指令更喜欢使用乘积规则，
and of course you should do that too. Given a fairly complicated expression like this,
当然，您也应该这样做。给出这样一个相当复杂的表达式，
you must try and use the best rules possible to get the most compact answer in the result
您必须尝试并使用最佳规则，以获得最紧凑的结果
because then you can use it much more easily in future work.
因为这样您就可以在以后的工作中更轻松地使用它。
Okay. Let’s go on now to talking about multiple compositions. The chain rule itself
好的。现在让我们继续讨论多种组合函数。连锁规则本身
talks about the derivative of f[g[x]] as being g'[x] times f'[g[x]], but of course that will hardly be
谈到f [ g [ x ]] 的导数是g '[ x ]乘以f '[ g [ x ]]，但是在实际的研究过程中
a chain which only has two links in it, so you can keep on this way and build up chains
很少遇到一个只有两个链接的链，因此您可以继续这种方式并建立越来越长的链
of longer and longer lengths. Let’s say that we’ve got f[g[h[x]]] like over here.
假设我们在这里有f [ g [ h [ x [ ]]]。
The derivative is going to be h'[x] and then g'[h[x]] and then f'[g[h[x]]]. In every case,
导数将是h '[ x ]，然后是g '[ h [ x ]]，然后是f '[ g [ h [ x ]]]。在任何情况下，
you fix the remaining functions or variables and work out derivative. For example, if I gave you
您都可以继续求出其余的函数或变量，并计算出导数。例如，如果我给你
Sin[Cos[x^2]] as your function, then the derivative would be 2x from the x^2, then −Sin[x^2]
Sin[Cos[ X ^ 2]]作为函数，那么导数将是2 x（由x ^ 2求导得到），然后-Sin [ x ^ 2]
from the cosine and then Cos[Cos[x^2]] from the outer sine wave. The answer over here
从余弦，然后来自外面套着的正弦，有Cos [Cos [ x ^ 2]]。
is confirmed by D, and that tells you that given any long chain of compositions,
这个结果可以有D指令验证。而对于任意给定的长链组合函数
you can apply just the same rule and get the result.
您可以应用相同的规则并获得结果。
A similar example is one I’ll take up next, which is CubeRoot[Cos[x^2]].
一个类似的示例是我接下来要讲的这个示例，它是CubeRoot [Cos [ x ^ 2]]。
Again, you start from the innermost function, x^2, then work out the next function derivative
同样，您从最里面的函数x ^ 2开始，然后算出下一个函数导数
in the chain and then the outermost derivative. The answer over here is a fairly complicated function,
然后是最外面的导数 答案是一个相当复杂的函数，
but D confirms that it is correct. You can plot the function and its derivative, and you get back
但是D确认它是正确的。您可以绘制函数及其导数，然后返回
this beautiful plot. Just to recall for you the procedure again, you work out the derivative of x^2,
这个美丽的绘图。只是为您再次调用该过程，您就能计算出x ^ 2 的导数，
the innermost one, work out the derivative of Cos[x] and replace x with x^2, and then finally
最里面的一个，求出Cos [ x ] 的导数，并用x ^ 2 替换x，最后
work out the derivative of CubeRoot[x] and replace x with Cos[x^2].
得到了CubeRoot [x ]的导数然后将x用Cos [ X ^ 2]替换。
Okay. As a final example, let’s talk about simple harmonic motion.
好的。作为最后一个示例，让我们讨论简单的谐波运动。
Simple harmonic motion is a motion that’s given by the scale of a trigonometric function.
简单谐波运动是由三角函数的缩放给出的运动。
Here A is the amplitude. Think about a pendulum. The amplitude is how far it goes in one direction.
这里A是振幅。考虑一下钟摆。振幅是它在一个方向上移动的距离。
ω is the frequency—that is, how fast it goes—and δ is the phase shift. You could have two pendulums
ω是频率（即频率有多快），而δ是相移。你可以有两个摆
and they both have drastic different motions because they have different phase shifts.
而且它们都具有截然不同的运动，因为它们具有不同的相移。
They started, say, at different times and you get different phase shifts.
例如，它们在不同的时间开始，并且您得到不同的相移。
Now given such a simple harmonic motion, you can work out the velocity and the acceleration
现在给出这样一个简单的谐波运动，您就可以计算出速度和加速度
by working out the first and second derivatives. Here are the velocity and acceleration,
通过计算一阶和二阶导数 这是速度和加速度，
v and A, and notice that the acceleration is almost the same as the position except that
v和A，请注意，加速度与位置几乎相同，除了
it has this − ω^2 multiplied to it as an extra factor. What that says
它有一个-ω^ 2乘以它作为额外因子。
is that s'' +  ω^2s[t] is equal to 0, and that’s something called a differential equation,
它表明是s ''+ω^ 2 s [ t ]等于0，这就是所谓的微分方程，
which you will study much later in calculus. The HoldForm does the following.
您将在以后的微积分学中学习。HoldForm执行以下操作。
It prevents anything from evaluating, so if you do ReleaseHold like I’ve done over there,
它会阻止任何计算，因此，如果像我在那儿一样进行ReleaseHold操作，
then in fact you get back the result True, which says that the differential equation is satisfied by
那么实际上您得到的结果为True，表示微分方程满足
the simple harmonic motion function over here.
这里简单的谐波运动函数。
Okay. That brings me to the end of today’s lesson. To summarize, the chain rule lets you
好的。这使我到今天课程的结尾。总而言之，链式规则可让您
find the derivatives of many more functions because you can work out
找到更多函数的导数，因为您可以计算出
the derivatives of products and powers, et cetera, much more easily with the help of this rule.
在此规则的帮助下，您能求出乘积和幂次函数的等等的导数。
Now of course you can build up a chain of any length so you can use it more than once
现在，您当然可以建立任何长度的链，因此可以多次使用
where a function is a composition of more than two functions. Those two statements
其中一个函数是两个以上函数的组合。
summarize the lesson, but today’s lesson is probably the most difficult one in our series so far,
以上两点总结了今天的课程，但是今天的课程可能是迄今为止我们系列中最困难的课程，
so do review it carefully, look at the exercises and make sure you’re ready for the next lesson,
因此，请仔细复习它，看一下练习，确保您为下一课做好了准备，
which is on implicit differentiation. I’ll stop over here.
下一节课将与今天讲的有一点点不同。好了，今天的课就到这里。